How do I loathe thee? Let me count the ways.
10 Things I Hate About You is a comedy, romance,
drama film directed by Gil Junger.
On the first day at his new school, Cameron instantly falls
for Bianca, the gorgeous girl of his dreams.
The only problem is that Bianca is forbidden to date until her
ill-tempered, completely un-dateable older sister Kat goes out, too.
In an attempt to solve his problem, Cameron singles out the only guy who could possibly be
a match for Kat: a mysterious bad boy with a nasty reputation of his own.
Patrick Verona, played by Heath Ledger.
Katarina Stratford, played by Julia Stiles.
Cameron James, played by Joseph Gordon-Levitt.
Bianca Stratford, played by Larisa Oleynik.
Michael Eckman, played by David Krumholtz.
Joey Donner, played by Andrew Keegan.
10 Things I Hate About You is a 1999 American teen romantic comedy film directed by Gil Junger in his film directorial debut and starring Julia Stiles,
Heath Ledger, Joseph Gordon-Levitt, Larisa Oleynik, Larry Miller, Andrew Keegan, David Krumholtz, Susan May Pratt, and Gabrielle Union.
The screenplay by Karen McCullah Lutz and Kirsten Smith is a modernization of William Shakespeare's
comedy The Taming of the Shrew, retold in a late-1990s American high school setting.
The film follows new student Cameron James (Gordon-Levitt) who is smitten with Bianca Stratford (Oleynik) and attempts to get bad boy
Patrick Verona (Ledger) to date her asocial sister Kat (Stiles) in order to get around her father's strict rules on dating.
Named after a poem written by Kat about her relationship with Patrick, the film was shot in the Seattle
metropolitan area, with many scenes filmed at Stadium High School in Tacoma, Washington.
Released on March 31, 1999, 10 Things I Hate About You grossed $53.5
million and received generally positive reviews from critics.
It provided breakthrough roles for Stiles, Ledger, and Gordon-Levitt, all
of whom were nominated for various teen-oriented awards.
Ten years later, it was adapted into a television reboot, which ran for twenty
episodes and featured Larry Miller reprising his role as Walter Stratford.
Since its release, the film has gained popularity as a cult classic, often
being cited as one of the greatest romantic comedies of all time.
The film explores themes of high school, deception, based on
play or musical, coming of age, teen movie.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.